(Translated) Alas!
น่าเศร้าใจเสียจริง
Two loving souls by death cruelly parted
วิญญาณรักสองดวงได้พรากจากกันอย่างโหดร้าย
In madness and grief, a dark path started
ความบ้าคลั่ง ความโศกเศร้า และความเกลียดชังได้ก่อตัวขึ้น
Calamity was drawn, rituals subverted
เพียงเพราะการสังเวยนั้น ได้นำมาซึ่งหายนะ
But by her cold steel was death averted
ถ้าไม่ใช่ด้วยคมดาบที่นางชักออก ผู้คนคงต้องล้มตาย
Mortal ties broken, with the adepti she went
พันธะทางโลกสิ้นสุดลง พร้อมชะตาต้องเซียนที่เริ่มต้นขึ้น
Their abiding place filling paternal bonds rent
ที่พำนักเซียนได้มาเติมเต็มสายสัมพันธ์
To her red strings of binding they sent
พร้อมใช้เชือกสีแดงพันธนาการเธอไว้
And they dwelt long together, content
ร่องรอยของอดีตพร่าเลือนเริ่มจางหาย
The crane returned to a home without luster
ครั้นนกพิสุทธิ์หวนกลับบ้านอีกครั้ง หาได้เจออดีตที่เคยเรืองรอง
The cobwebs overgrown, the grave-shrouds a-fluster
เจอเพียงหยากไย่พริ้วเรียกวิญญาณที่ลางเลือน
But one bond upon her
ชะตาที่ผูกพันกับทางโลก
This world could not muster
ได้สลายหายไปดั่งควัน
Thus does the Divine Damsel's tale duly end
เดิมทีเรื่องราวของ "เทพธิดาแห่งการทำลายล้าง" ควรจะจบลงเท่านี้
But today a new tale I have to append
แต่วันนี้ฉันจะขอเพิ่มอีกสักหน่อย
Which I shall now tell — if you shall attend
และขอขับร้อง... ให้ทุกท่านฟัง
From the world she seems apart
ณ โลกที่ดูคล้ายจะห่างไกลไร้คนเข้าใจ
But there are those who know her heart
กลับพบมิตรแท้ผู้รู้ใจ
With crimson spear and flashing brand
ด้วยหอกพู่สีแดงพร้อมดาบซึ่งทอแสงประกาย
To still the raging tides they stand
ร่วมขจัดกระแสคลื่นที่โหมกระหน่ำ
The crane once returned
เมื่อครั้งที่นกพิสุทธิ์หวนกลับ
And once, she was spurned
โลกกว้างนั้นไร้ที่พึ่งพิง
She turned, and left alone
แม้จากไปอย่างโดดเดี่ยว
Now, she might be found
วันนี้กลับพบพานอีกครา
With friends all around
ทั่วโถงเต็มไปด้วยเพื่อนพ้องรายล้อม
To whom she is bound — a home
อยู่พร้อมหน้ากัน ณ เวลานี้